What if every image could become a creature,
and learning a new format
made it stronger? This is PETBATTLE, an
education game about
understanding what you create.
Starting from a clean Level One session, I
switch to English and summon
a visual creation through the magic circle.
PETBATTLE turns visual
meaning into a bounded set of essences, then
shows only my own PET and
its explainable Physical, Magic, Defense,
and health parameters. File
size, image resolution, and raw token usage
never add battle power. The
complete CPU loop works on GitHub Pages
without an account or API key.
The opponent stays sealed until I enter the
colosseum. The camera
spirals down from an aerial view, my PET
arrives, and the rival is
revealed only at battle start. Physical
interrupts Magic. Magic pierces
Defense. Defense counters Physical. The
commands, health, effects, and
result all stay inside one readable arena
experience.
A result records bounded experience and
mastery for the actions I
actually used. One match cannot maximize the
PET. In this same clean
browser session, repeated real battles
reached one hundred ninety
experience and unlocked Core Level Two. The
roadmap connects each future
format to a concrete learning theme instead
of making it a cosmetic
upgrade.
Level Two opens a source-image-free SVG
Evolution Quest. I choose a
theme and a learning focus, then follow
Observe, Decompose, Build, and
Verify guidance. I explain why the model
remains readable at thumbnail
size, save the reflection as portfolio
evidence, and evolve the PET. The
unlock is not permission to upload a new
extension. It is a guided
reason to learn how that representation
works.
GPT-5.6 Luna is an optional semantic
interpreter behind a Cloudflare
Worker. It proposes a small structured
description. Zod validates that
response, and deterministic code calculates
the stats. The OpenAI key
never reaches the browser. When the model or
Worker is absent, the local
analyzer keeps the complete core game
playable. AI helps read meaning,
but it never becomes an opaque judge of
student work.
Codex was my primary engineering partner in
the main build thread. I
used it to redesign the unfinished concept,
implement the Three.js arena
and deterministic battle engine, create the
secure AI boundary, add
progression and the SVG learning quest,
write tests, perform browser
quality assurance, localize the interface,
generate the submission
media, and deploy the public app. I made the
product decisions that keep
it fair, explainable, and educational.
Today PETBATTLE teaches raster and vector
thinking. Next, the same loop
can unlock code effects, 3D models, PDF, and
IFC, each with its own
validator, learning objective, and creative
challenge. Understand what
you made. Learn a new way to express it.
Return to the arena.